Hartford Journeymen Plumbers and Apprentices, Local 76 Records 1984.0012
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Hartford Journeymen Plumbers and Apprentices, Local 76 Records
1909-1983
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0012
9 Linear Feet
This local was originally chartered on 1 March 1893 as Local 76 of the United Association of Journeymen Plumbers, Gas Fitters, Steamfitters and Steamfitters Helpers of the United States and Canada.
History
This local was originally chartered on 1 March 1893 as Local 76 of the United Association of Journeymen Plumbers, Gas Fitters, Steamfitters and Steamfitters Helpers of the United States and Canada. Local 76 is located in Hartford, Connecticut, and represents Hartford area plumbers and steamfitters.
Scope and Content
The collection includes minutes (which also include reports of the officers, financial reports, sick reports), correspondence, bylaws and working rules, strike assessments, membership dues payments and travel reimbursements.
Arrangement
Series I: Minutes (1909-1954) contains minute books of the regular membership meetings of Local 76. Minutes include reports of the officers, financial reports, sick reports, and correspondence with other locals. These minutes are organized chronologically.
Series II: Administrative Records (1950-1983) includes a 1983 revision of Local 76's Bylaws and Working Rules, a 1950 Agreement and Declaration of Trust between Local 76 and the Association of Master Plumbers of Hartford, strike assessments for the July to September 1968 strike, correspondence and reports. This material is arranged by type.
Series III: Dues Records (1919-1970) is arranged in two sub-series. Dues Ledgers (1919-1968) contains records of membership dues payments and travel reimbursements. There are several gaps in this sub-series: 1951-1954, 1957-1958, 1961-1962, 1965-1966. Collection Sheets and Cash Receipts (1960-1970) served as another form of recording dues payments. All material is arranged chronologically.
Acquisition Information
The records were deposited in the Connecticut Labor Archives 1n April 1984 by Patrick Quinn, Business Agent.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Labor unions; Societies; Plumbing industry; Plumbers; Hartford (inhabited place); bylaws (administrative records); Publications (documents); Labor union meetings; Financial Records; Administrative records; Connecticut (state); Pipe fitting; Steam-pipes; Labor; Strikes and lockouts; Apprentices; Association of Master Plumbers of Hartford.
- Series I: Minutes, 1909-1954
  - 1909-1924, (5 volumes) (Box 1)
  - 1924-1947, (4 volumes) (Box 2)
  - 1947-1954, (2 volumes) (Box 3)
- Series II: Administrative Records, 1950-1983
  - By-Laws and Working Rules, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Agreement and Declaration of Trust: Contract between Local 76 And the Association of Master Plumbers of Hartford, 1950
  - Strike Assessments, 1968 July - September
  - Designation for death benefits, 1957-1961
  - Pension Funds, 1975-1977
  - General Officer's Weekly Newsletter, published by U.A. National, Washington, D.C., 1960-1962; (2 folders)
- Series III: Dues Records, 1919-1970
  - 1919-1925, (6 volumes) (Box 5)
  - 1926-1932, (6 volumes) (Box 6)
  - 1933-1947, (25 volumes) (Box 7)
  - 1948-1949, (1 volume) (Box 8)
  - 1950, (1 volume) (Box 9)
  - 1955-1956, (8 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1959-1960
  - 1963-1964
  - 1967-1968
  - Collection Sheets and Cash Receipts
    - 1960-1968, (3 folders)
    - 1968-1970, (2 folders) (Box 11)